Guide to the Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Information Files, ca. 1890s-present AIS.Info.Files
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- P
  - Pittsburgh Tuberculosis Sanitarium (Pa.)
  - Pittsburgh Tunnel Company
  - Pittsburgh Union Passenger Station and Hotel (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Pittsburgh Veterans for Peace
  - Pittsburgh Vintage Grand Prix
  - Pittsburgh Women's Cultural Corporation
  - Pittsburgh Zionist District and Tri-State Zionist Region
  - Pittsburgh, Cincinnati, and St. Louis Railway Company
  - Pittsburgh's Lavender Left
  - Pittsburgh-Allegheny County Tourism Advisory Board
  - Planned Parenthood Center of Pittsburgh
  - Pleasant Hills Community United Presbyterian Church (Pa.)
  - Pliskover Free Loan Association
  - Plum (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Poale Zedeck Congregation; SEE Congregation Poale Zedeck (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Point Breeze (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Police Research Commission (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Pittsburgh (Pa.). Police Research Commission
  - Polish American Day (Kennywood Park (Pa.))
  - Polish Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Polish Hill (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Polish Hill Civic Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Polish National Catholic Church of America. Buffalo-Pittsburgh Diocese
  - Polish Women's Alliance of America
  - Polynesian Americans; SEE Pacific Islander Americans
  - Port Authority of Allegheny County
  - Postal Codes- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh- Directories
  - Presbyterian Beneficial Union
  - Presbyterian Lay Committee. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - Preservation Pittsburgh
  - Prince of Peace Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Progressive Labor Party
  - Project Equality of Western Pennsylvania
  - Project for the Economic Renewal of Communities (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Project Forward. Pittsburgh Office
  - Project Pacesetter
  - Project Understanding
  - Providence Presbyterian Church (McKees Rocks, Pa.)
  - Psychological Service of Pittsburgh
  - Public Auditorium Authority of Pittsburgh and Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Public Charities Association of Pennsylvania
  - Public Interest Research Group. Western Pennsylvania; SEE Western Pennsylvania Public Interest Research Group
- R
  - RIDC; SEE Regional Industrial Development Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania
  - Railroad- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh- Timetables
  - Rainbow Kitchen (Homestead, Pa.)
  - Rea Family
  - Reformed Presbyterian Theological Seminary (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Regional Industrial Development Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania
  - Rehabilitation Institute of Pittsburgh
  - Rehoboth Presbyterian Church (Westmoreland County, Pa.)
  - Reizenstein, Florence
  - Religion and Race Commission of Metropolitan Pittsburgh
  - Religious Society of Friends. Pittsburgh Monthly Meeting; SEE Pittsburgh Monthly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Respect, Inc.
  - Rice, Charles Owen, 1908-2005
  - Ridgway, Matthew B. (Matthew Bunker), 1895-
  - Ripon Society of Greater Pittsburgh; SEE Ripon Society of Pittsburgh
  - Ripon Society of Pittsburgh
  - River Boat Gambling; SEE Gambling on River Boats
  - River City Brass Band
  - Rivers of Steel National Heritage Area (Pa.)
  - Robin, John P., 1912-2000
  - Robinson (Allegheny County, Pa.: Township)
  - Robinson Township; SEE Robinson (Allegheny County, Pa.: Township)
  - Robinson United Presbyterian Church (Bulger, Pa.)
  - Rockwell International
  - Rockwell Manufacturing Company
  - Rodef Shalom Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Rodef Shalom Temple; SEE Rodef Shalom Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Rolling Rock Hunt Racing Association
  - Roselia Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Rosenbaum's Department Store (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Rotary Club of Pittsburgh (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Royal Order of Jesters. Pittsburgh Court No. 2
  - Rush, Molly
  - Ruthenian Americans- Pennsylvania
- S
  - SONO Institute for Human Potential
  - Sacred Heart- St. Peter Roman Catholic Church (Tarentum, Pa.)
  - Sacred Heart of Jesus Roman Catholic Church (Braddock Hills, Pa.)
  - Sacred Heart Roman Catholic Church (Jeannette, Pa.)
  - Sacred Heart Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Sadlowski, Edward
  - St. Adalbert Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Agnes Roman Catholic Church (Richeyville, Pa.)
  - St. Andrew Lutheran Church (Coraopolis, Pa.)
  - St. Ann's Roman Catholic Church (New Galilee, Pa.)
  - St. Anthony's Roman Catholic Church (Bridgeville, Pa.)
  - St. Anthony's Roman Catholic Church (Homestead, Pa.)
  - St. Anthony's Chapel (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Athanasius Roman Catholic Church (West View, Pa.)
  - St. Augustine Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Barnabas Free Home (Gibsonia, Pa.)
  - St. Benedict the Abbot Roman Catholic Church (McMurray, Pa.)
  - St. Benedict the Moor Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Bernard Roman Catholic Church (Mount Lebanon, Pa.)
  - St. Boniface Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Cajetan Roman Catholic Church (Monessen, Pa.)
  - St. Casimir Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Cecilia Roman Catholic Church (Rochester, Pa.)
  - St. Columbkille Roman Catholic Church (Imperial, Pa.)
  - St. Cyprian Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Edmund's Academy (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Elijah Serbian Orthodox Church (Aliquippa, Pa.)
  - St. Francis of Paola Church (Ford City, Pa.)
  - St. Gabriel Archangel Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Gabriel of the Sorrowful Virgin Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. George Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Gregory the Theologian Russian Orthodox Greek Catholic Church (Homestead, Pa.)
  - St. Helen Roman Catholic Church (East Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Hilary Roman Catholic Church (Washington, Pa.)
  - St. Hyacinth Roman Catholic Church (Monessen, Pa.)
  - St. Hyacinth Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Ignatius de Loyola Roman Catholic Church (Carnegie, Pa.)
  - St. James Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. James Roman Catholic Church (Wilkinsburg, Pa.)
  - St. John Capistran Roman Catholic Church (Upper Saint Clair, Pa.)
  - St. John Fisher Roman Catholic Church (Churchill, Pa.)
  - St. John Neumann Roman Catholic Church (Franklin Park, Pa.)
  - St. John the Baptist Byzantine Catholic Church (Lyndora, Pa.)
  - St. John the Baptist Byzantine Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. John the Baptist Roman Catholic Church (Baden, Pa.)
  - St. John the Baptist Roman Catholic Church (Scottdale, Pa.)
  - St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Milvale, Pa.)
  - St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Josaphat Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Joseph Roman Catholic Church (Cabot, Pa.)
  - St. Joseph Roman Catholic Church (Everson, Pa.)
  - St. Joseph Roman Catholic Church (O'Hara Township, Pa.)
  - St. Joseph Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Joseph Roman Catholic Church (Uniontown, Pa.)
  - St. Kilian Roman Catholic Church (Mars, Pa.)
  - St. Ladislaus Roman Catholic Church (Natrona, Pa.)
  - St. Leo Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Leocadia Roman Catholic Church (Wilmerding, Pa.)
  - St. Louise de Marillac Roman Catholic Church (Upper Saint Clair, Pa.)
  - St. Luke Roman Catholic Church (Carnegie, Pa.)
  - St. Luke's Cemetery (Woodville, Pa.)
  - St. Luke's International Hospital (Tokyo, Japan)
  - St. Malachy Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Margaret Mary Roman Catholic Church (Coraopolis, Pa.)
  - St. Margaret Memorial Hospital (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Margaret Roman Catholic Church (Green Tree, Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - St. Maria Goretti Chapel (Pittock, Pa.)
  - St. Martin Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Assumption Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Byzantine Catholic Church (Ambridge, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Byzantine Catholic Church (Monessen, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Byzantine Catholic Church (Trauger, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Help of Christians Roman Catholic Church (McKees Rocks, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Magdalene Roman Catholic Church (Homestead, Pa.)
  - St. Mary of Czestochowa Roman Catholic Church (New Kensington, Pa.)
  - St. Mary of Mercy Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Mary of the Mount Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Roman Catholic Church (McKeesport, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Roman Catholic Church (New Castle, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Mary Roman Catholic Church (Sharpsburg, Pa.)
  - St. Matthew Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Matthew Roman Catholic Church (Saltsburg, Pa.)
  - St. Michael Byzantine Catholic Church (McAdoo, Pa.)
  - St. Michael Roman Catholic Church (New Castle, Pa.)
  - St. Michael Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Michael's Young Men's Society (Sharpsburg, Pa.)
  - St. Nicholas Byzantine Catholic Church (McKeesport, Pa.)
  - St. Nicholas Croatian Catholic Church (Milvale, Pa.)
  - St. Nicholas Greek Orthodox Cathedral (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Nicholas Orthodox Church (Donora, Pa.)
  - St. Nicholas Roman Catholic Church (Nicktown, Pa.)
  - St. Nicholas Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Norbert Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Pamphilus Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Patrick Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Mount Lebanon, Pa.)
  - St. Peter Roman Catholic Church (McKeesport, Pa.)
  - St. Peter Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Peter's Episcopal Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Uniontown, Pa.)
  - St. Philomena Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Raphael Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Rita Roman Catholic Church (Munhall, Pa.)
  - St. Stanislaus Bishop and Martyr Roman Catholic Church (Calumet, Pa.)
  - St. Stanislaus Kostka Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Stanislaus Roman Catholic Church (Ambridge, Pa.)
  - St. Stephen's Episcopal Church (Wilkinsburg, Pa.)
  - St. Stephen's Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Teresa of Avila Roman Catholic Church (Perrysville, Pa.)
  - St. Thomas More Roman Catholic Church (Bethel Park, Pa.)
  - St. Thomas Roman Catholic Church (Footedale, Pa.)
  - St. Victor Roman Catholic Church (Bairdford, Pa.)
  - St. Vitus Roman Catholic Church (New Castle, Pa.)
  - St. Volodymyr's Ukrainian Orthodox Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - St. Winifred Roman Catholic Church (Mount Lebanon, Pa.)
  - SS. Cyril and Methodius Roman Catholic Church (McKees Rocks, Pa.)
  - SS. Cyril and Methodius Roman Catholic Church (New Brighton, Pa.)
  - SS. Mary and Ann Roman Catholic Church (Marianna, Pa.)
  - SS. Peter and Paul Orthodox Greek Catholic Church (Windber, Pa.)
  - SS. Peter and Paul Roman Catholic Church (Homestead, Pa.)
  - Salvation Army
  - Sarah Heinz House (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Scaife Family
  - Scanlon, Leo
  - Scanlon, Letitia F.
  - Schaffer, Harry H.
  - Scheffler, Conrad
  - Schenley Farms Civic Association
  - Schenley High School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - School of Advanced Jewish Studies
  - Schultz, Carl J.
  - Schwab Family
  - Scottish Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Seder, Isaac
  - Selavan, Ida Cohen
  - Seldom Seen (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Semple Street Food Co-Op (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Serb National Federation
  - Serb National Federation. Vivovdan Lodge No. 68 (Farrell, Pa.)
  - Serbian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Serenity House (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Seventh Avenue Hotel (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Sewickley (Pa.)
  - Sewickley (Pa.)- Biography
  - Sewickley Community Center (Sewickley, Pa.)
  - Shaare Torah Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shaare Zedek (Anshe Poland) Congregation; SEE Congregation Shaare Zedek, Anshe Poland (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shady Side Junior School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shadyside (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shadyside (Pittsburgh, Pa.)- Biography
  - Shadyside Action Coalition (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shadyside Hospital (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shadyside Information Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Shadyside Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Sharpsburg (Pa.)
  - Sharon (Pa.)
  - Sharon Community Presbyterian Church (Coraopolis, Pa.)
  - Sheffler, Conrad; SEE Scheffler, Conrad
  - Sheltered Employment Services for the Mentally Retarded of Allegheny County
  - Shoenberger Family
  - Shpikover Hilfs Verien
  - Singer Family
  - Sisters of Charity of Seton Hill (Greensburg, Pa.)
  - Sisters of the Holy Family of Nazareth. Pittsburgh Province
  - Sisters of the Holy Ghost
  - Slavic Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Slavic Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Slavjane Folk Ensemble
  - Slippery Rock Women's Liberation
  - Slovak Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Slovak Catholic Federation of America
  - Slovak Civic Federation of Allegheny County
  - Slovak League of America
  - Slovene Americans; SEE Slovenian Americans
  - Slovenian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Smaller Manufacturers Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Smith College Club of Pittsburgh
  - Smith Glass Company; SEE L. E. Smith Glass Company
  - Smithfield United Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Smithfield United Church of Christ; SEE Smithfield United Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Smithfield United Methodist Church; SEE Smithfield United Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Social Planning- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Social Registers- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Social Surveys- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Social Workers Club of Pittsburgh
  - Socialist Workers Party
  - Soho Community Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Soho Community House (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Soldiers and Sailors Memorial Hall of Allegheny County (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Solidarity (Organization: U.S.). Pittsburgh Branch
  - Solidarity Day Coalition (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Sons of Lithuania Society (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Hills Association for Racial Equality (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Oakland Citizens Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Side (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Side Arts and Crafts Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Side Hospital (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Side Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - South Ward School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Southeastern Community Guidance Association
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania; SEE Pennsylvania, Southwest
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission
  - Spang Family
  - Spanish Cultural Club of Pittsburgh; SEE club Cultural Espanol de Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Specter, Edward
  - Speer Family
  - Speer, Edgar B.
  - Squirrel Hill (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Squirrel Hill Urban Coalition (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - SS. [names]; FILED AS Saints
  - St. [name]; FILED AS Saint
  - Stadiums- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Standard Pressed Steel Company
  - Standard Steel Car Company
  - Standish Family
  - Stanko Family
  - Steel Industry Heritage Corporation
  - Steel Strike, U.S., 1919-1920
  - Steinmetz Family
  - Stone, Lauson
  - Storch's Sons, Inc.; SEE V. Storch's Sons, Inc.
  - Stout Family; SEE Miller Family
  - Strategy 21
  - Street-Railroads- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Strikes and Lockouts- Pennsylvania- McKees Rocks
  - Strip District (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Subways- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Sun Drug Co.
  - Swedish Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Swissvale (Pa.)
  - Symroski, Charles A.
- T
  - Tamburitzans; SEE Duquesne University. Tamburitzans
  - Temple David (Monroeville, Pa.)
  - Temple Emanuel of South Hills (Mount Lebanon, Pa.)
  - Temple Ohav Shalom (Allison Park, Pa.)
  - Temple Sinai (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Thorn Hill School (Warrendale, Pa.)
  - Three Rivers Arts Festival (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Three Rivers Regatta (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Together We Can of Pittsburgh, Inc.
  - Together, Inc.
  - Traffic and Transportation Association of Pittsburgh
  - Traffic Club of Pittsburgh
  - Transfiguration Roman Catholic Church (Mount Pleasant, Westmoreland County, Pa.)
  - Transfiguration Roman Catholic Church (Russellton, Pa.)
  - Transitional Services, Inc.
  - Travelers Aid Society of Pittsburgh
  - Tree of Life Congregation; SEE Congregation Tree of Life (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Tree of Life-Sfard Congregation; SEE Congregation Tree of Life-Sfard (McKeesport, Pa.)
  - Trinity Cathedral; SEE Trinity Episcopal Cathedral (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Trinity Episcopal Cathedral (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Trinity Episcopal School for Ministry (Ambridge, Pa.)
  - Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Tri-State Conference on Steel
  - Tropman, Elmer J.
  - Troy Hill (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Tuberculosis League of Pittsburgh
  - Turtle Creek Watershed Association
  - Twentieth Century Club (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Twenty-Five Club; SEE Magee Women's Hospital (Pittsburgh, Pa.). Twenty-Five Club
  - Typothetae of Pittsburgh
- U
  - Ukrainian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Union United Presbyterian Church of Robinson Township (McKees Rocks, Pa.)
  - Uniontown (Pa.)
  - United Black Front (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - United Citizens for a Cleaner Pittsburgh
  - United Engineering and Foundry Company
  - United Fund of Allegheny County
  - United Jewish Federation of Greater Pittsburgh
  - United Jewish Fund of Pittsburgh
  - United Mental Health Services of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - United Negro Protest Committee
  - United Polish Societies of Braddock, Pa.
  - United Presbyterian Church (Jackson Center, Pa.)
  - United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Presbytery of Pittsburgh
  - United Skillcrafts, Inc.
  - United Smoke Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - United States Steel Corporation
  - United States. Civil Air Patrol. Allegheny County Squadron
  - United Steelworkers of America
  - United Vocational and Employment Service
  - University Chinese Club of Pittsburgh
  - Urban League of Pittsburgh
  - Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh
  - Urban Talent Development Corporation
  - Urban Youth Action (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Ursuline Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- V
  - V. Storch's Sons, Inc.
  - Vaad Hakashruth (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Vanport Presbyterian Church (Beaver, Pa.)
  - Veteran Police and Firemen's Association of Pittsburgh and Allegheny County
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States. Allegheny County Council
  - Victorian Interior Restoration
  - Vidovdan Lodge No. 68; SEE Serb National Federation. Vidovdan Lodge No. 68 (Farrell, Pa.)
  - Vietnamese Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Vital statistics; SEE [Place name]- Statistics, Vital
  - Vocational Rehabilitation Center of Allegheny County
  - Volunteer Bureau of Pittsburgh and Allegheny County
  - Voters' League (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Vulcan Crucible Steel Company
- W
  - WDUQ (Radio station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - WPXI (Television station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - WQED (Television station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - WQED-FM (Radio station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Walton Methodist Episcopal Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Warder, Bushnell & Glessner Co.
  - Wards; SEE Election districts
  - Warner, J. C.
  - Washington (Pa.)
  - Washington County (Pa.)
  - Washington County Historical Society (Pa.)
  - Waterfronts- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Watson Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Weber's Jewelry Store
  - Weir, Ernest Tener, 1875-1957
  - Weirton Steel Corporation
  - Welfare Fund (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Welfare Rights Organizations of Allegheny County
  - West End (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - West Lawn United Methodist Church (West Lawn (Berks County, Pa.))
  - West Liberty (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - West Mifflin (Pa.)
  - West Overton (Pa.)
  - West Overton Museums (Scottdale, Pa.)
  - West Penn Hospital; SEE Western Pennsylvania Hospital
  - West View Park (West View (Pa.))
  - Western Pennsylvania Alliance Against Racial and Political Repression
  - Western Pennsylvania Alliance to Block Bork
  - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy
  - Western Pennsylvania Education Conference
  - Western Pennsylvania Genealogical Society
  - Western Pennsylvania Hospital
  - Western Pennsylvania Hospital. BirthPlace
  - Western Pennsylvania Humane Society
  - Western Pennsylvania Kennel Association
  - Western Pennsylvania National Bank Corporation
  - Western Pennsylvania Public Interest Research Group
  - Western Pennsylvania Safety Council
  - Western Pennsylvania School for the Deaf
  - Western Pennsylvania Solar Energy Association
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation
  - Westinghouse, George, 1846-1914
  - Westmoreland County (Pa.)
  - Westmoreland-Fayette Historical Society
  - Whitehall (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Wildsisters, Inc.
  - Wilkins (Allegheny County, Pa: Township)
  - William Penn Association
  - Winchester-Thurston School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Women Concerned for the Unborn Child (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Women's Agenda
  - Women's Club of Forest Hills (Forest Hills, Pa.)
  - Women's Club of Homestead (Homestead, Pa.)
  - Women's Health Services, Inc.
  - Women's Welsh Club of Pittsburgh
  - Women's American ORT. Pittsburgh Region
  - Women's Center and Shelter of Greater Pittsburgh
  - Wood Family
  - Wood Run Settlement (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Worker-Writer Conference (Pittsburgh, Pa.: May 14-17 1981)
  - World Affairs Council of Pittsburgh
  - World Federalists Association of Pittsburgh
  - World War, 1914-1918
  - World War, 1939-1945
- Y
  - YM & YWHA; SEE Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - YMCA; SEE Young Men's Christian Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - YMCA-YWCA Older Boy-Girl Conference
  - YWCA; SEE Young Women's Christian Association
  - Yablonski, Joseph A., 1910-1969
  - Yeshiva Schools of Pittsburgh
  - Young Democratic Club of Pittsburgh
  - Young Men's Republican Tariff Club
  - Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Young Men's Christian Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Young Socialist Alliance (U.S.)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Youth Guidance Inc.
  - Youth Mobilization for Soviet Jewry
  - Youth Opportunities Unlimited
  - Yugoslav Americans- Pennsylvania
- Z
  - Zatkovich, Gregory Ignatius, 1886?-1967
  - Zion Evangelical Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Zionist Council of Pittsburgh
  - Zip Codes; SEE Postal codes
  - Zoning law- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Zug Family